HASAN TAREK

USER EXPERIENCE DESIGNER



Experience Summary

I am a NYC based User Experience & Product Design professional with over 4+ years experience in various roles with increasing responsibilities, including mid size tech startup and media consulting experience. I practice user centered design principles basing design decisions on user needs and business goals. I am experienced in building and leading successful product design teams in a variety of global companies, startups, and nonprofit environments.

Work Experience

LEAD USER EXPERIENCE DESIGNER

Jun 2015 - Present

Venture Pulse Inc. [www.venturepulse.org]

Venture Pulse Inc. is an online platform for over 20K+ venture capital firm database. This platform serves venture capital profile and over 650k+ venture investments.

At Venture Pulse I lead the design team to conceptualize and design user-centric customer experiences, with expertise in the areas of information architecture, interaction design, and usability research and analysis. Currently, I am the Lead User Experience Designer At Venture Pulse (NY Office) reporting directly to the CEO. Leads project teams to conceptualize and design user-centric customer experiences, with expertise in the areas of information architecture, interaction design, and usability research and analysis. Solid design strategies on both existing design problems and new product ideas.

Major Duties:

- Design user interfaces that provide users with an interactive, informative and engaging experience
- Serve as a subject matter expert, providing actionable recommendations while taking into consideration business objectives and end user needs
- Interpret creative briefs and translate them into quality wireframes and prototypes
- Actively work with cross-functional teams to gain an understanding of the audience, clients business goals, key usability requirements, technical constraints and future needs

Actively improve the usability and desirability of applications in collaboration with cross-functional teams

- Oversee all elements of wireframe delivery to the development teams
- Work closely with the design team to create online prototypes for usability testing
- Analyze customer needs and task objectives to ensure relevant and goal-oriented experiences
- Communicate the functionality and components of interactive elements to crossfunctional teams including the development and stakeholders
- Provide team leadership and process governance in regards to managing all aspects of user experience
- Serve as a mentor to junior UX team members
- Serve as a knowledge resource for the latest trends and technologies for web/mobile interface design, conducting ongoing research of web-based user interface best practices
- Manage UX initiatives from the idea stage to final QA
- Lead user research projects, develop proposals, conduct usability sessions, analyze and report results

USER EXPERIENCE DESIGNER

Jun 2014 - Jun 2015

Venture Pulse Inc. [www.venturepulse.org]

Collaboratively administrate empowered markets via plug-and-play networks.

Dynamically procrastinate B2B users after installed base benefits. Dramatically visualize customer directed convergence

Efficiently unleash cross-media information without cross-media value.

Quickly maximize timely deliverables for real-time schemas. Dramatically maintain clicks-and-mortar solutions without risk

I joined Venture Pulse as a Information Architect. Venture Pulse had amazing growth during my one year period. I joined Venrure Pulse when it had 4 employees and by the time I promoted it had over 19 employees. As part of the Venture Pulse Product I helped build it's core

Database tool and beautiful designed Newsletter which was catered over 10K active user online.

Major Projects/Products at Venture Pulse :

- Venture Pulse Database software development and redesign.
- Venture Pulse Newsletter and blog design
- Venture Pulse Mobile site and ios App design
- Client site and Apps design

USER EXPERIENCE DESIGNER

Sep 2013 - Jun 2014

LBM, Contract Freelance Position [www.blouinartinfo.com] [www.artsalesindex.com]

maximize timely deliverables for real-time schemas.

Collaboratively administrate empowered markets via plug-and-play networks.

Dynamically procrastinate B2C users after installed base

Efficiently unleash cross-media information without cross-media value. Quickly

INTERFACE DESIGNER

Jan 2011 - Aug 2013

Freelance
[www.thegrahamandco.com]
[www.woodstock-inn-ny.com]

EDUCATION

National University, Dhaka, Bangladesh Dept. Of Computer Science

Bachelor In Computer Science

Year : 2006-2009 Major GPA : 3.40 ☐ Hasantarek.nyc@gmail.com

(347) 620-4064

Portfolio:Hasantarek.com

skills

USER RESEARCH
USABILITY TESTING
PERSONAS
SITEMAPS
CARDSORTING

CONTENT STRATEGY
INTERACTION DESIGN

USER FLOWS

LOW/HIGH FIDELITY WIREFRAMES
LOW/HIGH FIDELITY MOCKUPS

USER INTERFACE DESIGN

USER CENTERED DESIGN PROCESS

SCHEMATICS

documents

UX/PRODUCT REQUIREMENTS
GATHERING
DESIGN SPECS.
FUNCTIONAL SPECS.

tools

UADOBE FIREWORKS
ADOBE PHOTOSHOP
INVISION APP
SKETCH APP
JUST IN MIND
MAC
WINDOWS

extra curricular

AUDIO BOOKS
PODCAST
MOVIES
WORKOUTS
CRICKET
CHARITY